# NATHAN HEALEA

# Software Engineer | Full Stack Developer

**541-556-8689** 

www.nathanhealea.com

Eugene, Oregon

Driven, energetic Software Developer with a passion for developing applications that improve processes and user experience. Experienced with full stack technology and languages. Aims to utilize the latest frameworks and technology stacks to provide the largest availability and scalability to applications. Innovative thinker and quick learner that solves problems at hand while also future proofing for expansion of features.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Software Developer**

Maps Credit Union Mar 2022 - present

Working with an amazing team to create exceptional member interfaces with MAPS CU

#### **Full Stack Software Developer**

PacificSource Aug 2021 - Mar 2022

Working with an amazing team to provide better health, better care, and better cost to the people and communities we serve.

#### Software Engineer II

American Express (Contract) Sep 2020 - Aug 2021

Maintained enterprise software by expanding features per user request, fixing bugs, and enhancing code for maintainability. Works cohesively with a team of six to sprint plan, engage in feature design discussion, and provide time estimates of deliverables. Responsible for code reviews, testing, and deployment of Docker containers to Rancher environment. Documented standards, release processes, and application features. Responsible for creating branching strategy and standards for team members.

- Expanded Adhoc report querying user interface, which allowed users
  to create advanced queries by adding nested group by and order by
  clauses. In addition, implemented new service side logic to support
  advanced queries and future proof code to allow for additional
  advancements.
- Quickly mastered new skills and technologies to become a fully independent developer.
- Led NodeJS upgrade for enterprise software and provided documentation for developers used to upgrade local development environment.

## Software Developer II

Northwest Community Credit Union Sep 2020 - Aug 2017

Developed applications for internal business units and member facing products. Led deployment of applications into Microsoft Azure. Maintained legacy applications and databases and performed domain migrations for said applications. Promoted from Programmer Analyst in October 2019.

 Responsible for the architecture, development, and deployment of the first public facing serverless application hosted in Microsoft cloud by a credit union in the Pacific Northwest.

## SKILLS

### **Languages & Frameworks**

C# (.Net Core, APS.NET)

Javascript (Typescript, React, Vue, jQuery)

NodeJs (ExpressJS, Electron, Gatsby)

PHP (Drupal)

Python (Flak)

SQL (MSSQL, MySQL, Oracle, PostrgesSQL)

CSS/CSS3 (Bootstrap, Material Design, TailwindCSS, SCSS/SASS, LESS

HTML/HTML5

#### **Core Competencies**

Software Architecture (REST, API, Microservice, Monolithic)

Cloud Development (Azure, Google)

Database (RDMS, Procedure, Function, View, Management)

Project Management (Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall

Virtualization and Containerization (Docker, VM, Vagrant)

# **EDUCATION**

#### **BS in Computer Science**

Oregon State University

#### **AAS in Computer Programming**

Lane Community College

### Career Pathway Certificate in Advance Game Development C++

Lane Community College

# Career Pathway Certificate as a Database Specialist

Lane Community College

- Improved business processes by creating a full stack application to reduce a three-day, two-person manual process to an under fiveminute automated job.
- Developed and implemented Software Development Life Cycle to align with project management and business operations, including source code vulnerability using SonarCube, used during a successful audit.

## **Software Engineer**

Oregon State University Jul 2015 - Aug 2017

Responsible for the development of web applications to support research projects. Worked with researchers and stakeholders to define project requirements and timelines. Maintained and supported Drupal environments. Introduced and maintained source control software for the department

- Developed text analysis REST API service using a LAMP stack,
   Bootstrap, and jQuery along with corresponding Drupal module that consumed text analysis REST API and provided data visualization.
- Utilized Vagrant to build LAMP stack virtual machines that replicated production servers for local development, provided documentation on usage, and installed technologies.
- Analyzed XML files to construct MySQL database schema to simplify data for researchers. Developed Python scripts to parse and upload data. Developed administration portal using LAMP stack to review and fix inconsistency in data.
- Introduced source control software, GitHub, to department.
   Responsible to migrating legacy projects to Github and provided training to team members.

**Software Engineer** 

Oregon State University Mar 2015 - Jul 2015

**Web Developer** 

Simplified Computing LLC (Internship) Mar 2014 - Jun 2014

# PROJECTS

#### LibNav

Oregon State University (Valley Library) Sep 2016 - Jun 2017

Library Navigation application to help student, staff, and faculty, locate resource in the Valley Library at Oregon State University (OSU).

@NathanHealea

in/NathanHealea

@NathanHealea